https://www.hearingplanet.com/en/privacy-policy.html

Call
Call us now at:
1-888-807-8163
Send
Send a Message
Someone will reply within one business day.
Submit
HearingPlanet | Trust the Hearing Aid Brand and Accessory Professionals
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) discloses the privacy practices for the Hearing Planet website (the “Website”), operated by Sonova e-Hearingcare, LLC and its affiliates, successors and assigns (“the Company”, “we”, “us” or “our”) and our privacy practices related to information you provide to us through communications with our Personal Hearing Consultants that you call through the contact information displayed on the Website.
We wrote this privacy policy to help you understand what information we collect from and about you; how we use this information and the choices you have regarding such use; and other important information regarding our privacy practices. If you have any questions or comments about this privacy policy or the ways in which we use the information we collect from and about you, please do not hesitate to contact us using the information provided in the Contact Us section at the bottom of this privacy policy.
This Privacy Policy applies to information collected by this Website and information collected in connection with phone calls or interactions you may have with our Personal Hearing Consultants. It will notify you of the following:
What personally identifiable information is collected from you, how it is used and with whom it may be shared.
What choices are available to you regarding the use of your data.
The security procedures in place to protect the misuse of your information.
How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.
Collection of Information
Information You Provide to Us
We collect information you provide directly to us, such as when you complete a transaction;  you speak with and provide information to one of our Personal Hearing Consultants to receive information or a referral; or otherwise communicate with us.  This information may include your name, e-mail address, phone number, postal address, payment information, insurance information, online hearing test and lifestyle questionnaire results, hearing conditions and related medical information, and other information you choose to provide to us.
Information We Collect Through Your Use of Our Online Services
We also collect information automatically through the use of cookies and similar technologies on our online services, electronic communications and advertisements that automatically receive and track certain data about how you and other visitors interact with our online services, preferences expressed and settings chosen. For example, we may collect information about your device (such as your device and browser type, operating system, IP address, mobile network carrier, and device and advertising identifiers) and your use of our online services (such as access dates and times, online features or pages viewed, system activity and the third-party site or service you were using before interacting with our online services). In some cases we do this through the use of cookies, pixel tags, SDKs and similar technologies that create and maintain unique identifiers. To learn more about these technologies and our use of them, please see our Statement on Cookies and Similar Technologies below.
Use of Information
We may use the information we collect from and about you (and your device) to respond to your questions or comments; assist you with finding audiologist; fulfill orders; process payments; provide you with customized content, targeted offers and advertising through our online services, other sites and via e-mail or text message; contact you with information, newsletters and promotional materials from us or on behalf of our partners and affiliates; develop new products and services, and improve our existing products and services; address problems and review the usage and operations of our online services or business, and improve our online service content, products and offerings; protect the security and integrity of our online services and our business; respond to law enforcement requests and as required by applicable law, court order and governmental regulations; and as otherwise described to you at the point of data collection and in this privacy policy.
In addition to the purposes identified above, any information we collect may also be used for analytics purposes (e.g., evaluating website usage patterns and advertisement interactions) so that we can gauge the effectiveness of our programs and advertisements, and improve the usefulness of information presented to visitors.
Sharing of Information
We may share the information we collect from and about you (and your device) as described in this privacy policy or as described at the time of collection.
Information Shared by Us
Endorsed Local Providers. Per your request, our Personal Hearing Consultants will assist you in finding an Endorsed Local Provider.  In order assist you with this referral, we will provide the Endorsed Local Provider with your name, contact information, date of birth, insurance information, and other information you provide to our Personal Hearing Consultants. Please note:  these Endorsed Local Providers are not employed by or affiliated with the Company and we do not control how they use or maintain your information.
Affiliates. We may share information we collect from and about you (and your device) with a parent, subsidiary or affiliate entity within our corporate family. Any organization to which we provide such information is required to keep it confidential and to only use such information in accordance with this privacy policy.
Service Providers. In the course of doing business, we employ other companies and individuals to perform a variety of functions on our behalf. For example, we may provide the information we collect from and about you (and your device) to companies that host our online services or send communications on our behalf. These service providers may have access to information about you if it is needed to perform their functions for us such as processing your credit card information, but they are not authorized by us to use or disclose the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or to comply with legal requirements, and they are required to maintain the information in confidence.
Legally Required. We reserve the right to disclose information we collect from and about you (and your device) if required to do so by law or by a regulatory authority.
Sale. During the normal course of our business, we may sell or purchase assets. If another entity acquires us or any of our assets, information we collect from and about you (and your device) may be transferred to such entity.
Aggregated and Non-Identified Data
We may maintain aggregate data or other non-identified information about you, such as usage statistics, online traffic patterns and user feedback. In addition to using this aggregated and/or de-identified information for the purposes discussed in this privacy policy, we may disclose this information to third parties without restriction.  Additionally, we may also combine your information with data we collect or obtain from third party sources, such as credit reporting agencies, analytics providers, etc.
Analytics and Advertising Services Provided by Others
We may allow others to provide audience measurement and analytics services for us, to serve advertisements on our behalf on our online services and across the internet, and to track and report on the performance of those advertisements. These entities may use cookies, pixel tags, SDKs, and other technologies to identify your device when you use our online services and interact with our electronic communications and ads, as well as when you visit other online sites and services. Data collected and maintained by such third-party ad providers will be subject to the terms of use and privacy policies of those providers. For more information about these technologies and service providers, please see our Statement on Cookies and Similar Technologies below.
California and Delaware “Do Not Track” Disclosures
California and Delaware law require us to indicate whether we honor “Do Not Track” settings in your browser concerning targeted advertising. At this time, there is no worldwide uniform or consistent industry standard or definition for responding to, processing, or communicating  Do Not Track signals. Thus, like many other websites and online services, we do not currently respond to any Do Not Track browser requests.
California Privacy Rights
Under California law, California residents have the right to request in writing from businesses with whom they have an established business relationship, (a) a list of the categories of personal information, such as name, email, and mailing address, and the type of services provided to the customer, that a business has disclosed to third parties (including affiliates that are separate legal entities) during the immediately preceding calendar year for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes and (b) the name and address of all such third parties.  To request the above information, please email us at: ContactUs@hearingplanet.com with a reference to California Disclosure Information. Please note that we are only required to respond to each customer once per calendar year.
Information Security
We and our third party providers use physical, technical and administrative security measures, consistent with industry practice. Such measures are reasonably designed to protect information we collect from and about you (and your device) from loss, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. We may use encryption, password protection, secure socket layers, internal restrictions and other security measures to help prevent unauthorized access to the information we collect from and about you. However, any information you provide to us is at your own risk. We cannot guarantee that such information will not be lost, accessed without authorization, disclosed, altered, or destroyed.
COPPA (Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act)
Our online services are not intended for or designed to attract children under the age of 13.  We do not knowingly allow children to order our products, communicate with us, or use any of our online services. If you are a parent and become aware that your child has provided us with information, please contact us using one of the methods specified herein, and we will work with you to address this issue.
Third-party links
Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or services on or linked to our Website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.
Your Choices
You can do the following at any time by contacting us via the email address or phone number identified at the end of this privacy policy:
See what data we have about you, if any.
Change/correct any data we have about you.
Have us delete any data we have about you.
Express any concern you have about our use of your data.
You may also "opt-out" of receiving marketing e-mails and other marketing communications from us by using the unsubscribe feature included in the e-mails we send.
Please refer to our Statement on Cookies and Similar Technologies for more information about your choices regarding cookies and similar technologies.
Statement on Cookies and Similar Technologies
We utilize Google Analytics, a web analysis service provided by Google, in order to better understand your use of our Website. Google Analytics collects information such as how often users visits the Website, what pages they visit and what other sites they used prior to visiting. Google uses the data collected to track and examine the use of the Website, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google may use the data collected on the Website to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to the Website is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of Use and the Google Privacy Policy. Google offers an opt-out mechanism for the web available here.
Cookies, web beacons, Flash cookies and similar technologies serve many important functions that help us serve you better. However, you have a variety of tools to manage cookies and similar technologies, including:
Web browser controls to block and delete cookies, or adjust your tracking preferences;
Visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance's opt-out page here to opt out from receiving third party advertiser cookies;
For information on how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies, click here.
Not Medical Advice; Not Responsible for Endorsed Local Providers
You acknowledge and agree that neither the Company nor its Personal Hearing Consultants are offering you any medical advice. While the Personal Hearing Consultant may provide suggestions in connection with referring you to an Endorsed Local Provider, any information a Personal Hearing Consultant provides you is strictly informational and is not a medical service.  In the event that you are seeking hearing or other medical services, please contact a medical service provider or specialist.  Although the Company may make the information you provide to it available to a Endorsed Local Provider, you acknowledge and agree that this information is based largely on your own submissions and may not be the most current data.  The Endorsed Local Provider is not employed by the Company.  The Company makes no representations or warranties with respect to the performance of, and is not responsible OR LIABLE for the acts or omissions of the Endorsed Local Provider.
Visiting The Site From Outside The United States
This Website is directed only at customers in the United States. If you are visiting the Website, or any part thereof, from outside of the United States of America, please be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored or processed in the United States. By using any portion of the Website, you understand and consent to the transfer of your information to the United States and those third parties with whom we share it as described in this Privacy Policy.
Changes to this Privacy Policy
We may change this privacy policy from time to time. If we make significant changes in the way we treat your information, or to this privacy policy, we will provide you notice through the relevant online services or by some other means, such as e-mail. Your continued use of our online services after such notice constitutes your consent to the changes. We encourage you to periodically review this privacy policy for the latest information on our privacy practices.
Contact Us
If you have any questions about this privacy policy or our other information practices, please contact us at ContactUs@hearingplanet.com
Last updated: July 2017
